<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Infosec on Abdul Samad</title>
    <link>https://terminal.samad.uno/term-sub/tags/infosec/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Infosec on Abdul Samad</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 01:45:48 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://terminal.samad.uno/term-sub/tags/infosec/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding EDR: A Deep Dive</title>
      <link>https://terminal.samad.uno/term-sub/posts/2025-02-16-edr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 01:45:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://terminal.samad.uno/term-sub/posts/2025-02-16-edr/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;understanding-endpoint-detection-and-response-edr-a-deep-dive&#34;&gt;Understanding Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR): A Deep Dive&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Endpoint Detection and Response (EDR) solutions have become a cornerstone of modern cybersecurity, offering advanced threat detection, investigation, and response capabilities. Traditional antivirus (AV) and endpoint protection platforms (EPP) focus primarily on signature-based detection, but EDR extends these capabilities by incorporating behavioral analysis, threat hunting, and real-time monitoring to detect advanced persistent threats (APTs) and sophisticated cyberattacks.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This article provides a deep technical dive into EDR architecture, detection methodologies, evasion techniques, and countermeasures.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Zero Trust Security Architecture</title>
      <link>https://terminal.samad.uno/term-sub/posts/2025-02-15-trust/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 01:45:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://terminal.samad.uno/term-sub/posts/2025-02-15-trust/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-zero-trust-security-and-why-you-should-adopt-it&#34;&gt;What is Zero Trust Security and Why You Should Adopt It&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-zero-trust-security&#34;&gt;Understanding Zero Trust Security&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Zero Trust Security is a cybersecurity model that operates on the principle of &amp;ldquo;never trust, always verify.&amp;rdquo; Unlike traditional security models that assume entities inside a network are trustworthy, Zero Trust requires continuous authentication and authorization of every user, device, and system attempting to access resources. It minimizes risk by enforcing strict identity verification and limiting access to only what is necessary.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Metasploit for SOC Analysts</title>
      <link>https://terminal.samad.uno/term-sub/posts/2025-02-12-meta/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 01:45:48 +0530</pubDate>
      <guid>https://terminal.samad.uno/term-sub/posts/2025-02-12-meta/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;metasploit-for-soc-analysts-leveraging-offensive-tools-for-defensive-security&#34;&gt;Metasploit for SOC Analysts: Leveraging Offensive Tools for Defensive Security&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Metasploit is often regarded as a penetration testing framework, primarily used by red teamers and ethical hackers to exploit vulnerabilities in networks and systems. However, for Security Operations Center (SOC) analysts, understanding Metasploit is equally valuable. By leveraging Metasploit, SOC analysts can simulate attacks, analyze attacker behavior, and improve incident detection and response strategies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This blog will explore how SOC analysts can use Metasploit effectively to enhance their defensive capabilities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
